{
    "id": "d36370a209ab4717a8f55434cf198770",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She is interested  ………………………. to cook.",
            "description": "The adjective interested is followed by in + noun/-ing form. ",
            "answers": [
                "to learn",
                "to learning",
                "in learning"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "b5f721719e4a45f085ae6c0b867526da"
        },
        {
            "question": "She didn’t look happy ………………………….. me.",
            "description": "The adjective happy is followed by a to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "seeing",
                "to see",
                "to seeing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "21dc156d7f6345ff8ceaaf6fbd9ad7b4"
        },
        {
            "question": "That car is new, …………………………?",
            "description": "We use a negative tag after an affirmative statement.",
            "answers": [
                "is it",
                "isn't it",
                "doesn't it"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "482ff194d5124ffa84c9941908e74e1f"
        },
        {
            "question": "It was …………………………… that I could hardly work.",
            "description": "The structure is so + adjective/adverb + a/an + noun.",
            "answers": [
                "a so warm day",
                "so warm a day",
                "so a warm day"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1e9d5716d05e40c9b2c7ac5e54487cff"
        },
        {
            "question": "They were …………………………… injured in the accident.",
            "description": "Deadly is an adjective and it means fatal. The adverb for this meaning is fatally.",
            "answers": [
                "deadly",
                "fatally",
                "deathly"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5d16f48bf2eb47f9a965dfd473c429e9"
        },
        {
            "question": "I very much enjoy …………………………….",
            "description": "The verb enjoy can be followed by a noun/pronoun/-ing form. It cannot be followed by an infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "to swim",
                "swimming",
                "swim"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c1089a68bcc34d7e8bdf987f009d2da0"
        },
        {
            "question": "He would never ……………………………… if he hadn’t changed jobs.",
            "description": "The sentence is in the type three conditional. Here we use a past perfect in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the result clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have promoted",
                "have been promoted",
                "had been promoted"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "fbbb5b26b2134faa8e8a1a42f58e8700"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t trust god men. I never have, and I ……………………………..",
            "description": "The rule of parallelism. ",
            "answers": [
                "will never",
                "never will",
                "never would"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8f758928d66e4a36903cbeed422b3eb2"
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was ………………………….. I was working.",
            "description": "The structure is/am/are etc. + … age is used without a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "your age",
                "at your age",
                "of your age"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6b1eaf914f9443d78cb92411b4ab34f5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Alice isn’t here today. Mary isn’t here ………………………………",
            "description": "After mentioning a negative idea or fact, we can add another negative point by using not … either.",
            "answers": [
                "either",
                "neither",
                "nor"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "578f8029aa704f6d94277ccda6ff269c"
        },
        {
            "question": "He often comes and …………………………… the evening with us.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "spend",
                "to spend",
                "spending",
                "spends"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "07968c0957ba4e6f9976210f3145919d"
        },
        {
            "question": "We didn’t have ……………………………. trouble going through the customs.",
            "description": "Any suggests an indefinite quantity or number. It is often used in questions and negative clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "any",
                "some",
                "no",
                "enough"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6bb39f8738b241e59b95521b24116326"
        }
    ]
}